optoutprescreen.com 2013-09-01

# OptOutPrescreen.com - Frequently Asked Questions

**Opt Out Services LLC** is a joint venture among Equifax Information Services, LLC, Experian Information Solutions, Inc., Innovis Data Solutions, Inc., and TransUnion, LLC (collectively the "Consumer Credit Reporting Companies"). Through the OptOutPrescreen.com website, you may exercise your right to Opt-Out, which is a term for removing your name from receiving firm offers of credit or insurance based on your credit information with the Consumer Credit Reporting Companies, Equifax, Experian, Innovis and TransUnion. Opt Out Services’ primary purpose is to accept and process requests from consumers to "Opt-Out" of receiving firm offers of credit or insurance. 

Opt-In is a term for including your name on firm offer lists of credit or insurance based on your credit information with the Consumer Credit Reporting Companies, Equifax, Experian, Innovis and TransUnion. If you have previously completed a request to Opt-Out and would like to Opt-In, you may also complete your request on this website. 

You may also "Opt-In" or “Opt-Out” by dialing 888-5-OPT-OUT (888-567-8688). 

Please carefully read our privacy policy to understand how we will treat the information you provide while visiting this website. This policy may change from time to time. Please check the policy each time you use our website for the most current information. If changes to the policy do occur, the date of revision will also be shown. 

This privacy policy applies only to Opt Out Services and the information that you provide at this website. In the event you visit the websites of the Consumer Credit Reporting Companies, please note each of these companies maintain their own privacy policies which can be found at their respective websites. Opt Out Services is not responsible for the privacy practices or content of the Consumer Credit Reporting Companies' websites, or other linked sites listed on these web pages, if any. 

Safeguarding the privacy of your personal information, both online and offline, is an important priority for you and for the Consumer Credit Reporting Companies. Accordingly, reasonable steps are taken by Opt Out Services to: 

  * Give you, as a visitor to this website, clear notice when information is requested from you, the types of information requested from you, the general purposes for which that information will be used or disclosed, and the categories of users to whom the information is provided; and 
  * Use safe and secure systems, physical and electronic, designed to safeguard the information about you. 

This privacy policy applies to Opt Out Services and the processes in which we manage online requests from consumers to "Opt-Out" of firm offers of credit or insurance or to "Opt-In", and transmits those requests to the Consumer Credit Reporting Companies for fulfillment. 

  * The Information Collected About You
  * How Information Collected From You is Used
  * To Whom the Information Collected from You may be Disclosed
  * Security and Confidentiality Note
  * Children's Privacy
  * Keeping Up-to-Date on our Privacy Policy Changes
  * How to Contact Us with Questions or Comments

**The Information Collected About You**

The Opt Out Services privacy policy applies only to your use of this site and to all information received online from you and about you in connection with an online transaction on this website. Opt Out Services also may receive information from you about an online transaction if you send emails. Other than in the situations described below, no personally identifiable information from or about you is collected while you are accessing and using this website. 

Specifically, information is received from you when you request to Opt-In or Opt-Out through this website. In order to locate your consumer credit file and to process your request, you will be asked to provide information. ****

The specific information collected from you online for processing of your requests includes: 

  * First and last name (middle initial and suffix, as applicable) 
  * Social Security Number 
  * Date of Birth 
  * Current mailing address 

In addition, we may collect general Internet data, including your domain name (e.g. AOL, Earthlink, etc.), the web page from which you entered our site, the date and time you visited our website, the type of web browser you used, which of our web pages you visited, and how long you spend on each page. To collect this information, when you visit our website, a "cookie" may be set on your computer. Cookies contain a small amount of information that allows our web servers to recognize you whenever you visit. We use the information we collect to fulfill your requests and to study how this site is used. Doing so allows us to improve and enhance your experience on our website. We do not provide this information to outside parties other than for such reasons. No personal information is stored in cookies. 

**How Information Collected From You is Used**

We use the information we collect about you in connection with your request by providing it to the Consumer Credit Reporting Companies. Non-personally identifying information is also used in connection with monitoring, maintaining and improving this website, as well as other services that are necessary or incident to fulfilling your request. 

**To Whom the Information Collected from You may be Disclosed**

Any of the information collected from or about you, as described above, may be disclosed to any of the Consumer Credit Reporting Companies. 

Opt Out Services or the Consumer Credit Reporting Companies, may also disclose any of the information collected, as described above, to affiliates of the Consumer Credit Reporting Companies, which are companies that are related to one of them by common ownership or affiliated with one of them by common control, or to the associated consumer reporting companies who utilize a nationwide consumer reporting company system and that may have information about you. 

The information collected, as described above, may also be received by third parties providing services to Opt Out Services in connection with processing your requests (for instance, the entity hosting our website). 

Each third party receiving this information is required to either: (i) abide by the restrictions in this privacy policy and is not permitted to use or disclose the information for any purpose other than as described in this policy; or (ii) receive and use the information in compliance with the Fair Credit Reporting Act, Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act and other regulatory and legal requirements. 

Any of the information collected may also be disclosed in response to valid legal process, including but not limited to a lawfully issued subpoena, search warrant, regulatory investigation or inquiry, or court order. 

**Security and Confidentiality Note**

Opt Out Services recognizes the importance of secure online transactions, and we use security technologies to safeguard the information you provide us through this website. When we transmit your information to the Consumer Credit Reporting Companies, your information is encrypted. In addition, we take other reasonable physical, technical, and procedural safeguards for purposes of safeguarding your personally identifiable information. 

**Children's Privacy**

The Opt Out Services website, where personally identifiable information in conjunction with requests to Opt-In or Opt-Out is collected, is intended for use only by adults. Opt Out Services complies with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act and does not knowingly solicit or collect information from children. For legal and security reasons additional information will be collected to authenticate the validity of requests to Opt-Out for children under 13 years of age. For this reason such requests must be made through the mail. Please refer to the FAQ How do I complete an Opt-Out request by mail for a child under 13 years of age?

**Keeping Up-to-Date on our Privacy Policy Changes**

Opt Out Services wants you to be fully informed about how it will protect your privacy. Opt Out Services may change its privacy policy from time to time, but it will not change its practices until they have been posted at this website. If changes occur, the date of revision will also be shown. By providing your information to us, you agree that we may notify you of changes in our privacy policy through this website. 

**How to Contact Us with Questions or Comments**

If you have questions or comments about the Opt Out Services online privacy policy, please write to Opt Out Services at:  
Opt-Out Department  
PO Box 2033-A  
Rock Island, IL 61204-2033

We cannot process Opt-Out requests received at the above address. All Opt-Out requests must be submitted through this website or through our toll-free telephone number, 888-567-8688. 

If you have specific questions about your credit file, you should contact the Consumer Credit Reporting Companies directly. 

Last updated February 11, 2008
